You said you wanted more picks, right?
>> Uh we went the other way. We started to
watch for No. Uh Malachi Fields is a
player that um you know we coveted
coming into the draft and as things
started to fall and he was still there
and you know you know some of the
receivers that had win already. um you
know, an opportunity to go get him. And
you know, we thought the value was we we
were fine with the value and the ability
to secure the player that we wanted at a
position that you know, we wanted to
upgrade um you know, not only the the
size, length, athleticism, another
phenomenal kid that um you know will
come in and be be a really good uh
addition for us.
>> How much?
>> You said you were fine with the value,
but you've always talked about the 27
draft like it's this all world draft
class. Was that a consideration at all?
>> Yeah. And you know, we'll see. I know
the the comp formula, we'll see if we're
able to still get one there. So, I you
know, there's there's a chance we could
maybe get a a comp formula for a pick
for Well. So, you know, you may get one
for one there. But, um, as we've seen
throughout the draft, we've had
opportunities to move back and, you
know, fours, five, sixes. If if you want
to be, you know, intentional about it,
you can certainly do that earlier in the
draft, move back a couple spots. So, um,
you know, just excited to get the player
that we're able to get. How much was
this the kind of receiver you were
looking for to maybe compliment? You
have like Mooney and Slay or kind of
vertical stretch receivers and he's
obviously a great receiver, not biggest
guy in the world. He obviously fits a
certain build and mold. Is that how much
was that what you were looking for
specifically?
>> Yeah, certainly a different body type
than we currently have. So, yeah, adding
that was um you know, something that we
we had talked about doing. Uh we weren't
going to force it unless you know the
value was um at at the right spot. And
you know, obviously being 6'4 and a
half, you know, 218 lbs and the catch
radius, um, and athleticism that he
displays was was attractive. All those
things were, you know, almost like build
the basketball team. We talk about, you
know, you got to power forward now.
>> What was I think you guys didn't go to
the senior bowl, right? You guys were
here, but he had like some like standout
senior bowl. What was the word from the
scouts after that?
>> Best receiver down there was was the
reports back. Yeah. co coach and I uh
were here that week, but you know, we
obviously got to go go through the film
and watch the one-on- ones and the
practices and the games and um you know,
he he had a phenomenal week down there
for sure.
>> Jackson,
>> yeah, you can put it in the radius, you
know, put it in the area, you know, and
he's he's going to come down with a lot
of times and you saw that Notre Dame um
you know, just again down, you know, a
down the field target um that can come
down with the ball in contested
situations. red zone, you know, big body
in the red zone. Um, again with that
tremendous catch radius, you know,
that's that's invaluable for for a young
quarterback.
>> John, you mentioned last night getting
more stout. You add another big player
like how much do you like having four
more big players, four or five more big
players?
Yeah, it's uh it's not a it's not a
negative, you know, it's definitely not
a negative, but uh we spent a lot of
time over the course of the whole draft
and I think the scouts did a great job
once again, but today was a day spent
looking at opportunities throughout the
day and we were all in there together
studying these guys and you try to reset
it and and uh Malachi was a guy that we
had right at the top of our board from
the beginning of the day. You know, it
wasn't it wasn't a guy that we weren't
targeting. we were targeting him right
out of the gates and we were able to get
Colton and he was in the same clump. You
know, I think Joe did a great job of
understanding, you know, kind of the the
draft and where people valued certain
players and thought we could get them a
little later. Um, we probably exhausted
as far back as you thought we could go
>> and then made an aggressive move to come
back up and get to this spot right here.
You know, a whole a whole round of head
head where we were picking to give us a
chance to get him. So, he's a guy that
we were we were, you know, we felt,
honestly, we felt like had for us maybe
a second round value. We we wanted the
player and we got him. I thought it was
a was a is a great a great get for us.
>> How much were you considering maybe
going after that number 37 versus
>> Say again.
>> Uh considering getting him uh at 37
versus
>> Yeah, Colton was our top guy on the
board coming into the day, so we were
excited to get him.
>> Yeah. I mean, I think that part of it's
like it's not just about like how much
you value them. It's about what where
where can you get them, you know? Right.
>> Yeah.
>> And and and you know, Joe and the rest
of the scouting department, they do a
great job of kind of analyzing all that
stuff. Sometimes you're not right, but
>> they kind of had it pegged in terms of,
you know, where he was going to go in
the order and and uh that's probably why
we got it done.
>> John, Joe mentioned, you know, catch
radius for young quarterback. What is
that? I mean, I know what it means, but
can you explain as a head coach now how,
you know, in a young quarterback's head,
he can throw the ball in the air and
he's like,
>> I know he's going to catch it. You know,
>> it's such a great point because the idea
being basically a player is never
covered, you know, because you throw the
ball to him, he's going to find a way to
make the play around the defender and
not just not, you know, just he's got
he's got reach, he can outreach
whoever's whoever's covering him. He's
got great hands. He's a contested type
of receiver. You've seen those guys in
the league for a lot of years, make a
lot of plays. And and I would also say
too, you know, I heard what some of the
commenters said, and you know, the 40
time is a concern for people, but when
you when you do the miles per hour,
which we get to tracking now, that's
fast. And he he tracks a lot faster.
He's it's equivalent of a of a mid44
type 40 time. He's running over over 21
miles an hour consistently in games.
He's also got the ability to stop, drop
his weight, change direction, get out of
brakes. you see all that. We looking at
one-on-one tapes from college and things
like that. And I think he's kind of an
underrated athlete as well. So, we'll
see when he gets here. We'll all get a
chance to look at him and see what he
see what he does. But plus, he's an A+
personality, A+ character, A+ worker.
They love him at Notre Dame. So,
looking forward to getting the room.
>> Any hesitation that there's going to be
such a large gap between this pick now
and I believe they don't pick till
beginning of the sixth. Mhm. Yep. We
have three three six round picks. So,
yeah, big gap in between there. So,
we're probably not going to do anything
before that. I can I pretty much assure
you that. So,
>> did that did you have to think hard
about that if the idea of okay, we're
not going to be able to pick for a while
now?
>> Yeah, there's some guys coming off now.
I mean, it's it's a little bit of the
wild wild west right now on our board.
So, you know, there was a player up
there that we coveted and, you know, we
felt really good if we were able to get
him get him in the building and um you
know, we'll just continue to to chip
chip away with the three three picks
remaining and then college free agency
and then, you know, any vets that are on
the street. If we need to continue to
fill the roster that way, we'll we'll do
that.
>> How do you feel I'd be asking this
question? If you picked your defensive
tackle, I'd probably be asking about
wide receiver. So, I'll just ask it the
other way. How do you feel about
defensive tackle now? Obviously, it's
hard to fill all the needs with only so
many picks, but that seems to be the one
area you guys haven't addressed.
>> Yeah, and we uh again, not playing till
September. There's there's other avenues
that we can do it. You know, again, some
of the free agents that are on on the
street, you know, we'll we'll continue
to talk to some of those guys and um you
know, again, we got college free agency
and you know, three six round picks. So,
um you know, we'll we'll find a way. We
we won't stop. We'll keep looking to
upgrade not just the tackle, but the
entire roster. You know, wherever it is,
we'll continue to do that.